Mahesh Raj Mainali

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- +1 226-927-5143
- developer@maheshrajmainali.com.np
- www.maheshrajmainali.com.np
- in www.linkedin.com/in/mahesh-rajmainali/
- 145 Arbour Glen Crescent, London, Ontario, Canada

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Engineering

2010 - 2015

Pokhara University, Nepal

.NET Programming

NIIT, Kathmandu, Nepal June 2013

SKILLS

- Logical Thinking
- Effective Communication
- Front End and Back End Development
- Mobile Development
- Responsive Web Designing
- Code Review

TECHNOLOGIES

- .NET Framework (C#)
- SQL Server
- JavaScript/JQuery
- HTML & CSS
- Tortoise SVN/ TFS/ GIT
- DevExpress/DevExtreme
- Visual Studio
- LINQ/XML
- API/Windows Service
- Agile

PROFILE

Highly self-dedicated, energetic Software Developer with more than 5 years of programming experience and more than 3 years of professional software development experience working on Microsoft technologies such as C# programming, ASP.NET Webforms, .NET Framework, Relational Databases (SQL), Internet Information Services (IIS), Team Foundation Server, Mobile Application Platform (Xamarin) and other technologies such as JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Web Services. Other qualities include:

- Quick learner, adaptive with new technologies and always in the front row to tackle with competitive and challenging works.
- Collaborative with a team as well as capability of working independently, multi-tasking, excellent attention to detail, work under pressure and work to deadlines.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer / Mobile

Enliv Information Technologies Lalitpur, Nepal

2017 - 2018

- Implemented users' requirements and features in new or existing modules.
- The proven role for research and development of the mobile applications by adopting emerging technology as per client requirements.
- Introduced methodologies and best practices among the team that enhanced product definition, release processes and submission of the product before the set deadline.
- Participated in a team meeting and provided strong views and demonstration about the changes need to be acquired for the projects.

Software Developer

Nepasoft Solutions Pvt. Ltd. Kathmandu, Nepal

2015 - 2017

- Performed well by designing, coding and testing new and existing web modules by effectively following the instruction in the documentation.
- Accomplished frontend design tasks and integrated custom user interface like custom modal box, custom wizard control, custom API to the project.
- Outperformed on most of the tasks assigned creatively.
- Reviewed codes of the teammates by testing the changes made and giving feedback in person or commenting in their task.

ACTIVITIES AND INTEREST

- Volunteered as a Mentor for Canada Learning Code for the event Ladies Learning Code: HTML & CSS for Beginners: Learn to build One Page Website from scratch. (27 April 2019).
- Completed online course Learn ReactJS (Codecademy).
- Self-learned and implemented new technologies such as ReactJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, Git, GitHub, Heroku.
- Interest on researching and implementing new technologies in existing or new projects.